

Senthilkumar Sivaraman

🃤 3131 Timmons Ln, #2201, Houston, Texas 🗓 +1 832 630 9407 🖾 senthilkumar150393@gmail.com

⊕ github.com/senthilsivaraman 🖭 senthilsivaraman.github.io 🏜 senthilkumarsivaraman (LinkedIn)

SUMMARY

Full Stack Engineer with 4+ years of work experience in product development and research. Seeking a challenging developer position in an organization that rewards dedication and proficiency in .Net, Angular and Sitecore development with opportunity to learn new technologies in Cloud and Artificial Intelligence.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Computer Science, University of Houston, Texas, USA Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science, Anna University, Chennai, India

May 2019 April 2014

JOB EXPERIENCE

Dating App - Independent, Houston, USA - Co-Founder

September 2019 – Present

- · Performed planning, requirements gathering, design, development, unit testing and deployed in Azure server and in custom domain.
- Implemented JSON web token (JWT.io) based Authorization to the service endpoint.
- Created TypeScript reusable components and services to consume REST API's using Component based architecture provided by Angular8
- Created a controller and its endpoints using Web API methodology of different HTTP verbs in developing Web services using .Net core 3.0
- · Successfully implemented functions like chat, like, upload pictures, last seen, read receipt and filters

Tardis Inc, Houston, USA - Research Consultant

January 2019 - June 2019

- Returned values by strengthening our co-op members' ability to anticipate and adapt to changing markets, economies, environments and technologies
- Developed results-driven research architecture processes
- Performed requirement analysis for both functional and non-functional requirements
- · Built strong client relationships thus ensuring active and impactful client business engagement and project activity involvement

Element Blue Houston, USA – Sitecore Developer

 $October\ 2018-December\ 2018$

- Experienced in developing Information Architecture, Templates, Layout, Sub layout, Renderings using ASP.NET Sitecore MVC
- Developed and delivered a module using PowerShell to automate the basic Sitecore operations for internal purpose which reduced 85% of work time
- Experienced in writing re-direction rules, configure URL routing and Sitecore Workflows
- Involved in daily scrum calls with the client to gather requirements
- Analyzed and resolved client tickets within defined SLAs

University of Houston, Houston, USA - Instructional Assistant

October 2017 - September 2018

- Enhanced and Maintained the university student center website
- Provided solutions on SQL Server using stored procedures and joints for optimizing data retrieval on web applications
- Additionally, Relationship Manager In-Charge, managing two entire building, supporting the students and overseeing \$200K worth equipment as a team
- · Assessed and effectively solved customer challenges and constantly sought new ways to exceed customer expectations

Independent Contractor, Tirupur, India – Software Developer

September 2016 - May 2017

- Performed planning, development, testing and deployed software applications in client locations
- Successfully converted the Business Requirement into Technical Solutions
- Delivered and maintained Inventory management and Accounts management software which saved 210 man-workhours and salary per month
- Created the guidance document on how to use the application and the new features added
- Received client's appreciation for optimization and fixing critical issues

Procter & Gamble - Mindtree, Bangalore, India –Software Engineer

October 2014 - June 2016

- Developed platform to integrate Sitecore, .net and content
- Responsible for every part of Sitecore implementation starting from creating templates, creating items and standard values and different versioned content
- Designed and developed the information architecture of the Sitecore data templates and renderings
- Implemented Rating and Reviews using Bazar voice, Sitemap and redirection rules
- Worked in localization, deployment, maintenance, documentation and support after the software release
- Provided Sitecore training to the clients and helping them to perform basic operations on their own

SKILLS

Programming Languages: C#, C/C++ Frameworks: ASP.NET Core, MVC, Web API, Angular 2+, Bootstrap Scripting Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Python(Basics) Markup Languages: HTML5, XML Database: SQL Server, SQLite Tools: Sitecore, Visual Studio, VS Code, JIRA, GitHub, SVN Miscellaneous: OOPS, SCRUM, CSS, IIS, Entity Framework, LINQ, ¡Query

CERTIFICATIONS

Sitecore Experience 9 Solution Developer, ASP.NET Core, Angular, Bootstrap, AWS(Basics), SQL

PROJECTS

Gillette, Tampax, Herbal Essences, Vicks, Pantene, DNOW, Mitel, Using AI to solve pick up drop world, Inventory and Accounts Management